# **SUMMARY**

An Electrical and Computer engineer graduate with 2 years of professional experience looking for internship or a full time or co-op position in Computer Engineering or Data Analytics. Areas of interest include machine learning, data analytics and web development (including database) with proficiency in javascript, python, HTML and SQL. Highly flexible in working both independently and as a team member.

#### **EDUCATION**

## Purdue School of Engineering and Technology, IUPUI

Masters in Electrical and Computer Engineering

Expected Graduation May 2018

Current GPA: 3.37

# • National Institute of Technology, India

Bachelor of Technology in Electronics and Communication Engineering

July 2013

## **SKILLS**

\_Hands on experience with UI development and MVC frameworks like CodeIgniter, Laravel Javascript, Python, Django framework, Jquery, SQL, HTML 5, PHP, CSS, SASS Matlab, Pycharm IDE, Microsoft Office, Microsoft Visual Studio, Eclipse, Netbeans, Google API, Wireshark, Vmware workstation, latex

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

# Institute for American Thought (IUPUI)

Web Interface Programmer
Working on Scholarly Text Editing Platform application for TEI XML encoding

Feb 2018-Present

#### **Ericsson India Global Services (Network Engineering)**

Network Engineer, Technical Engineering Team

Apr 2014-July 2016, India

Worked closely with the Technical Engineering Team and developed Web based networking tools for network analytics, monitoring call drops and neighbor cells optimization in a network. These tools are successfully functional in Ericsson.

#### **Internships**

Seven week on the project practical training at Indian Institute of Technology, Kanpur (IITK) on control of devices using bluetooth protocols.

Jan 2011-March 2011, India

Studied the communication system and ground station activities of JUGNU nanosatellite launched by IITK in collaboration with Indian Space & Research Organization (ISRO).

### **PROJECTS**

### **Current Academic Projects**

Implementing machine learning algorithms for network traffic data analytics. Thesis area: Exploring personalized host based anomaly detection.

Published research paper "Identify the Maximal Cluster of Hosts based on Data Fusion and Machine Learning Algorithms for Intrusion Detection", at The IEEE International Conference on Big Data Security on Cloud (BigDataSecurity 2018), Omaha, NE, USA.

Authorship Attribution: Applied various machine learning techniques for classifying text fragments from multi topic books of different authors.

Statistical machine learning models for training real data sets and text data.

#### Academic

Developed a web application using cryptography algorithms for secure communication between two online parties.

Worked on ns-3 simulator to implement and compare the performances of various routing protocols in an ad-hoc network.

Internet of things project using PIR sensor, FRDM-K64F board and ESP 8266 Wi-Fi module.

#### **Professional**

Analytical Coverage Display (ACD): User management portal and modules based on predefined network KPIs for geo-spatial network analytics.

Ericsson Mapping Analytics (EMATIX): Tool to display neighbor data on the google maps which is used for analyzing and optimizing networks. Addition, deletion of neighbor cells in a site mapped to various technologies like GSM, CDMA, WCDMA and vendor specific operations are achieved from this.

Ericsson System Performance Analyzer(ESPA): Module to find out the down cells in a network which are affecting the nearby cells and displayed like a live presentation.

SoftHuman: Developed java plugin for excel files automation.

Nerve: Comprehensive Web tool for assessment of employees in .net and java (model in MVC structure) jsp and html.

Teaching Assistant/Grading Assistant | Indiana University Purdue University (IUPUI) Fall 2016 – Jan 2018

✓ Mentored students in learning Fundamentals of Electrical Engineering.

## **ACCOMPLISHMENTS**

Rockstar performer award for exemplary cost saving & revenue generation by way of innovative solutions at ERICSSON.

Dancing – Contemporary, Kathak, Freestyle, Did stage performances for supporting NGOs for unprivileged kids-BOSCO in Bangalore, India (<a href="https://www.facebook.com/1234LetsDance">www.facebook.com/1234LetsDance</a>).